RICHARD VERDIER FULL STACK DEVELOPER

▼ rverdi643@gmail.com

In-Progress

6825590833

in

https://www.linkedin.com/in/richard-verdier-2990b61

• https://github.com/rverdi642

I have spent the last 10yrs as a solutions focused manager for large brand clients (e.g. Schlumberger, McGraw-Hill, Siemens N.A.). The opportunities afforded me to large successes included migrating distributed computing centers to consolidated cloud computing environments, as well as implementing server management software that delivered cost reductions, efficiencies and transparency for the client.

I am now augmenting my operational skills, with a Full Stack engineering background through my Lambda School education, looking to align business needs with the appropriate technology solution.

Skills

TECHNICAL

Javascript (ECMA 5 & 6)

Bootstrap 4

React 16.8

Django 2.1

Python 3

Express 2.8

knex 0.16

React-router-dom

PostgresQL

Axios 0.18

CSS/HTML

Stripe Payment API

Ubuntu

Styled Components

Education

Lambda School Academy of Computer Science and Web Development June 2018 to Current Recently graduated from the Lambda program for Full Stack Web Development and Computer Science(algorithms & data structures)

Currently in the Next program related to career search mentoring.

University of Houston - Downtown

76 hours towards a degree in Applied Mathematics

Employment

Atos Inc

Service Delivery Director -Siemens sector

Arlington, Texas Oct. 2007 to Oct. 2017

- Led migration from current mode toolsets to future global tools (monitoring Nagios/ SCOM and patching -SCCM/ManageSoft)
- Responsible for delivering Vendor Security Bulletins to all servers in the North America landscape.
- Successfully managed the onboarding of Siemens acquisitions into the contracted landscape.
- Managed and recruited onshore/offshore delivery teams (Mexico & India)
- · Simultaneous team support for both current mode and future mode tools until global migration complete
- · Delivered service level attainment reporting for delivery services, as measured against those contracted.
- Manged monthly accruals and those forecasted for global delivery services, reduced global re-charges by 10% as a result, for a 35K per month savings
- Manage Atos Application Technical resources(Web/DBA/ATM) for contracted application support.
- Negotiate non-standard service and pricing agreements for application support varying from the standard contract offering

Manager - Server Tools/Automation

Arlington Texas Oct. 1998 to Oct. 2007

- Managed client monitoring new initiatives as wells as steady state.
- Developed internal tools and interfaces with a number of clients, in coordination with their internal tooling
- Migrated to Open Source tooling (Hyperic) resulting in a \$1.1Mil/yr cost saving
- Team developed interfaces from CA USD 6.0 ticketing system to various customer supported help desk request systems.

Projects

Lambda Labs Project - Don't Send That Email

Jan. 2019 to Feb. 2019

github.com https://github.com/Lambda-School-Labs/dont-send-that-email

Don't Send That Email helps users send messages to coworkers, family or friends that convey the right tone. Sometimes it's hard to intepret the emotional message of an email or text. DSTE uses an Al (IBM Watson tone analyzer) to preview the emotional tone of a message.

 The project used a realistic team based development approach having received specification for an application with paid services

The technology stack components used were Front-End (React, React Router, React Bootstrap, Axios, CSS), for the Backend - (ExpressJS, NodeJS, Passport, Knex, Bcrypt PostgresQL).

- My contributions included the Stripe payment integration, navigation, and UI additions/modifications
- Heroku and Netlify were used for the front and backend services respectively

Lambda Notes Front End Final Project

Aug. 2018 to Aug. 2018

github.com https://github.com/rverdi642/front-end-project-week

The main objective for the project is to develop the MVP feature set listed below using react and any other technologies learned at Lambda School. Design files were provided as a creative guide creative guide.

Bash Git Redux

NodeJs

NON TECHNICAL

Client Assessment and Analysis Deployment management Application management Self_motivated Process Implementation Enterprise monitoring Enterprise patch management Budgetary management

• Trello board created with cards that provided the list of MVP features that would be tracked the states Backlog, To Do, In Progress, and Done

MVP Display a list of notes

- - [] Create a note with a title and content
 - [] View an existing note
 - [] Edit an existing note
 - [] Delete an existing note

Enterprise Monitoring Cost Reduction

2005 to 2006

I was presented with cost reduction target of \$1.2M, I made the decision to terminate the maintenance costs for all commercial use software used in the management of customer servers and move to Open Source software

Development and Deploy Enterprise Request System

2007 to 2008

Established a project that gathered requirements from the Remedy Help desk system stakeholders in preparation for migration to a Computer Associates web client based request system. The resulting discovery required over 900 hrs of product customization and development. The actual migration took 8 months based on the ability of clients to migrate and train on the new system.